Dennis Masao

Full Stack developer

✓ dennismasao96@gmail.com

+1 (321) 257-8668

Reston, VA, United States

Scid.f1913e34003f018f

SKILLS

Language

Javascript, TypeScript, Erlang, Elixir, HTML, CSS, Python CSS4, ECMAScript(ES6), TypeScript, GraphQL, HTML5, Java, SCSS

Frameworks

React, Cypress.io, Django REST Framework, Phoenix Web Framework, Flask, Redux, Express.js, MUI, Bootstrap, Next.js, React Native, Boost, Nest.js

Libraries/APIs

Antd, REST APIs, Flask-RESTful, React, Node.js, Redux-Saga, Vue, Highcharts, AmplifyJS, Vue2, Redux Form, Reselect, RxJS, Three.js

Tools

MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose, Celery, Redux Thunk, SendGrid, Webpack, VS Code, Atom, Figma, AdobeXD

Platforms

Android, Amazon Web Services(AWS), Firebase, Shopify, Twilio, Google Cloud Platform(GCP), Docker, AWS Lambda, Blockchain, MacOS, Ethereum

Storage

NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore, MongoDB, Elasticsearch

Other

TypeORM, Hooks, AWS, Material Design, Firebase Cloud Functions, Front-end, Blockchain Development, Apollo, Semantic UI, Microsoft Azure, Linux Administration, Progressive Web Application(PWA), Windows 10

PROFILE

I have 8 years of experience in web development using JavaScript(React, Vue), Python(Django), and AWS. I have worked on a variety of projects at companies of all sizes. I have been an important problem solver in the teams and never failed to deliver quality work with my work and problem-solving skills. I cares about user-friendliness and the performance of your application.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior React Developer, *Neighborhoods.com/CA, USA* 2020 – 2022

- Worked on the real-estate website with React, Redux, SCSS, Webpack.
- Created Figma wireframes to plan out the layout and structure of the website, including placement of buttons, text, images, and other interactive components ensuring a seamless UX
- Interpreted the Figma design into mobile-firstresponsive front-end UI.
- Optimized React UI with lazy-loading and modern browser APIs.
- Delivered new features and the storybook build component with optimization.

Senior Full-stack Developer, Care Of/NY, USA 2020 – 2020

- Developed a Quora-like site using React, React Hooks front end with GraphQL for a home-care service company based in Australia.
- Implemented mobile-responsive front-end pages with React, Bootstrap, and SCSS.
- Used Apollo-boost to consume GraphQL API.
- Engaged back-end development in Nest.js and PostgreSQL.
- · Integrated third-party APIs like Sendgrid.

Full-stack JavaScript Expert, Roubler Pte Ltd/New South Wales, Australia

2019 - 2019

- Developed USA's leading cloud-based workforce management, HR, and payroll software with Angular, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, and more.
- Worked closely with web development and software design team for production, modification, and maintenance of web applications.
- Developed and unit-tested software that meets business requirements and technical design. Maintained code coverage quality for all new components built close to 90% with an emphasis on TDD.
- Built great-looking software with technologies like Bootstrap to the dynamic back end in Socket.IO.
- Troubleshot pre- and post-production implementations.

PROJECTS

Neighborhoods.com LLC *⊘* React, Redux, Redux Thunk, SCSS, JavaScript, Webpack, CSS

Care Of ∂

GraphQL, PostgreSQL, SendGrid, Node.js, SCSS, Bootstrap, NestJS, Boost...

Cyop Protocol *⊘*

React, Redux, Ethereum, Smart Contract, ERC20, Web3, Javascript, CSS

Learn with Socrates *∂*

React, Material UI, Redux, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Django, Javascript, Python

N·Ef·Ti ∂

React, Redux, Non Fungible Token, Smart Contract, Firebase, Web3, Javascript, Webpack, CSS

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science, *Chiba University* Japan

LANGUAGES

Japanese

English

Chinese

React, Node.js Developer, *FinaText / Chiyoda, Japan* 2018 – 2019

- Joined the team as a React and Node.js developer with cryptocurrency experience.
- Implemented React High-Order-Components along with Antd.
- Implemented REST APIs with FeathersJS.
- Wrote Blockchain-related helper functions.
- Worked on the styling of React components along with Styled-components.
- Used Enzyme, Jest, and Chai for the test and Lerna for packaging resources.

Full-stack Developer, *NashTech/Chiba, Japan* 2016 – 2018

- Built front-end pages with Bootstrap, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Integrated a lot of data from different data sources like "world bank" to a database using Python packages such as Numpy and Pandas Data Reader.
- Worked on an image processing project with OpenCV and JavaCV like crowd detection.
- Contributed to JSP projects with Apache Tomcat. Worked on WPF animation and desktop applications.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Landing Page Development

By invitation of my friend, I have developed landing page of a blockchain fitness project he was working.

University information System

As a student, I joined volunteer team to develop and maintain university website using PHP Laravel Framework